<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Food on nico-series</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/food/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Food on nico-series</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/food/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chorizo Soup</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/chorizo-soup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/chorizo-soup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;servings--time&#34;&gt;Servings &amp;amp; Time&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Makes 10ish bowls / fills the red pot. Assume around 3 hours in the kitchen, as you need to chop veggies, cook meat, and clean up.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;choosing-ingredients&#34;&gt;Choosing Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chorizo is the star of this soup. It&amp;rsquo;s packed full of flavor, so you don&amp;rsquo;t have to work as hard to come up with flavors on your own. Look for fresh sausages from the butcher if possible.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chicken thighs are used to bolster the soup and add protein while not going quite as hard on cholesterol as a chorizo-only soup would. Thigh meat stands up to cooking down in soup better than breast does, so we prefer it to breast meat here. Bone-in thighs also have more flavor, so I use those and do the extra work of deboning and shredding at the end of the recipe. If you want to skip deboning, you can just use boneless thighs instead.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fall Braised Pork</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/fall-braised-pork/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/fall-braised-pork/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;servings--time&#34;&gt;Servings &amp;amp; Time&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Makes 10-15 servings. Start a day and a half before you want to eat it as it will sit in the refrigerator, then the oven, for a very long time.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This goes well on rice or sandwiches, with fresh slaw or a salad.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;brine-ingredients---use-a-beer-bottle-to-avoid-dishes-&#34;&gt;Brine Ingredients - use a beer bottle to avoid dishes :)&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;48oz Yuengling beer (4 beer bottles)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;32oz apple cider (3-4 beer bottles)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;80-92oz water (7-8 beer bottles)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;12oz sugar (1 beer bottle)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;12oz salt (1 beer bottle)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1 tbsp cloves&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;braised-pork-ingredients&#34;&gt;Braised Pork Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1 8-10lb brined pork shoulder&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;24 oz chopped carrots&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;6-8 celery sticks, chopped&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2 large onions, chopped&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1 peach, sliced (optional)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;24-32 oz Yuengling beer (2-3 beer bottles)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;24-32 oz apple cider&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1 drizzle of Worcestershire sauce (at least a few tablespoons)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2+ tbsp salt&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2+ tbsp pepper&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1+ tbsp brown sugar&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1 dusting of paprika&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1 dusting of allspice&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;3+ tbsp pork rub of your choice&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2-3 tbsp of a high-heat tolerant oil&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;peach-sauce-ingredients&#34;&gt;Peach Sauce Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;3 peaches, skinned and chopped&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1-3 shots of bourbon whiskey&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2-3 tablespoons brown sugar&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;brining-directions&#34;&gt;Brining Directions&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Prepare your pork shoulder. If yours was frozen, it only needs to be partially thawed before brining, as the thaw time can incorporate into the brine time.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Rub the shoulder down with the dry ingredients first, poking the cloves into the meat.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Set the shoulder into a large stock pot, then slowly pour the wet ingredients into the pot around the shoulder to avoid disturbing the rub, alternating alcohol &amp;amp; cider with water to keep the 50/50 water/not water ratio consistent.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Leave it in the refrigerator for 8-24 hours.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;braising-directions&#34;&gt;Braising Directions&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cut your oven up to 275 degrees F.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Move your chopped vegetables into the braising pan and make a nice bed for the meat.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Retrieve your brined shoulder and drain the brine. Rub it down with a healthy coating of salt, pepper, and a nice pork rub. I had one on hand that was a garlicky mesquite, with smoked paprika, brown sugar, etc.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Get your largest skillet roaring hot, then pour in a drizzle of oil that handles heat well and drop the meat on there.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Laugh because your skillet is too small and you don&amp;rsquo;t have the correct tools to flip the meat. That&amp;rsquo;s ok, just carefully move the meat with your hands. The shoulder is large enough that by the time you get each side seared, a different side is cool enough to grab without burning yourself.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Alternately, you could have the correct tool, probably a salad claw or some grilling tongs.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Alternately, you can skip this step. Searing does add to the flavor, but this recipe is still highly edible without it.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I wash my hands a lot while cooking and you probably should too.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Relocate your now seared and fragrant pork to its veggie bed in the braising pan, fat cap side up. The fat will baste the rest of the meat while cooking and help to keep it moist.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Pour beer and apple cider into the braising pan until it&amp;rsquo;s been filled 1/3 to 1/2 of the way up. Keep in mind that the pork will release a lot of liquid, and if you fill the dish too high it may overflow. If you like, arrange some peach slices on top of the pork. They will cook down to nothing, but the juice should incorporate nicely.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cover the dish and pop it in the oven for 5-6 hours, checking every so often to make sure that the liquid levels are good and to check the doneness.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Once it seems to be around 2/3 of the way done, slice a crisscross pattern into the top and pat in a few tablespoons of brown sugar, a dusting of paprika and allspice, and a nice drizzle of Worcestershire sauce. Put it back in for another hour or so, or until you can easily tear off pieces with a fork. You&amp;rsquo;ll want it somewhere between roast and pulled pork consistency.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Let it rest, begin prepping sauce.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Serve with rice and a dollop of peach sauce.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;peach-sauce-directions&#34;&gt;Peach Sauce Directions&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Heat a small sauce pot on medium-low (4) heat.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add the peaches to the pot with a splash or 3 of bourbon, then slowly incorporate the brown sugar to taste.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cook down until the sauce reaches a pleasant spreading consistency and the alcohol taste of the bourbon is gone.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;try&#34;&gt;Try&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Try pureeing the peaches before adding them into the sauce pot. This brings them to a sauce-like consistency faster, and allows you to make a thinner sauce if desired because you won&amp;rsquo;t have to cook out as much liquid to get it spreadable.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Loaded Baked Potato Soup</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/loaded-baked-potato-soup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/loaded-baked-potato-soup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;servings--time&#34;&gt;Servings &amp;amp; Time&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Makes 8 respectable bowls, it&amp;rsquo;s about 3 hours in the kitchen if you count bacon, veggie chopping, and cleanup.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;choosing-ingredients&#34;&gt;Choosing Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Pick your potato of choice. Oftentimes, I go with &lt;strong&gt;red potatoes&lt;/strong&gt; because I like their texture. However, a grainier, starchier potato will soften up and break down into the soup a little more, so if you like a thick, starchy soup, a &lt;strong&gt;russet potato&lt;/strong&gt; may be to your preference.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
