<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Food on nico-series</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/food/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Food on nico-series</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/food/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Baked Potato Soup</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/baked-potato-soup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/baked-potato-soup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;baked-potato-soup&#34;&gt;Baked Potato Soup&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;servings--time&#34;&gt;Servings &amp;amp; Time&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Makes 8 respectable bowls, takes about 3 hours total if you count bacon time.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2-3 lbs small red potatoes, cut to 1.5 inch pieces&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1 lb thick cut bacon (can swap or add your choice of chopped sausage to this, it will flavor the soup)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1 yellow onion, chopped&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;5 sticks celery, chopped&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1 c of baby carrots, chopped&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1 head broccoli, break up florets to be small bites&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1 bundle of green onions, chopped &amp;amp; separated white from green&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1 heaping tbsp. minced garlic&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;48 oz chicken broth (can add 1/2 cup water if it cooks down, but no more)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;5 heaping tbsp. flour&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;16 oz sour cream&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;4 tbsp butter&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2 cups of milk&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1 cup of shredded cheddar&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;garlic powder&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;salt&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;black pepper&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;directions&#34;&gt;Directions&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cook the bacon, &amp;amp; set aside to cool, toss most of the grease but leave a coating in the pan.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add the garlic and onion to the same pan on medium, cook until onion is translucent.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Move onion &amp;amp; garlic to soup pot, add chicken broth and potatoes and get it bubbling gently for 10 mins.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add all chopped veggies except the onion greens &amp;amp; broccoli. Cut the heat to medium (6).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;After another 5-10 mins add salt, pepper, and garlic powder to taste. Add the broccoli and reduce heat to med-low(4). The earlier you add it in, the more it will break up.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In the meantime, lazy rinse the pan &amp;amp; chop the bacon.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Melt the butter in it and slowly whisk in flour and milk, keep it smooth. Add the sour cream after you have some milk in bc IDK if it will scorch. Add in cheddar cheese last. You want it to thicken up a some, but not pudding or paste thick.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The veggies should be cooked and the potatoes should easily smoosh with fork. The broth should have boiled down a fair bit to where some of the veggies poking above it. Stir in the butter sauce and bacon and cook for a few minutes until it is thoroughly combined. Keep in mind that it will continue to thicken after it is taken off the heat. Cut off heat and let it cool, stirring every few mins.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Top with onion greens and serve.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;alternate---chicken--potato-soup&#34;&gt;Alternate - Chicken &amp;amp; Potato Soup&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t add in as much chicken broth, stick to around 4 cups. Maybe fewer potatoes? When you would add in bacon, add in the cooked chicken as well.  You can also add peas and/or green beans, but later on, around the time you&amp;rsquo;d add broccoli.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
